Contact

apc1177@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/akeesa-bryan-rn-ba-ms-2817b0b1 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare Hospitals Patient Safety

Akeesa Bryan RN, BA, MS

Registered Nurse/Mentor/Founder of The Gift of Mentoring Charlotte, North Carolina Area

Summary

During my journey as a Registered Nurse for over 17 years, I have experienced seismic personal losses that have become the platform for milestone accomplishments. The passing of my husband 9 years ago was one of those losses, not only personally but professionally. We were both nurses and at that time he was my main support as I grew into my profession. During the healing process, I have been blessed with the wonderful opportunity to meet and work with amazing nurses both in the United States and abroad.

Throughout my career I have observed the lack of diversity among new nurses entering this profession. I have come to the realization that minority nurses are struggling academically and are not graduating at the same rate as their peers. This knowledge coupled with my passion to create an environment in which I can provide encouragement to these students during their academic journey has become my purpose in life.

In 2017, I founded the Gift of Mentoring. My mission is to provide student nurses of color with the support and guidance needed to successfully complete their educational goals through MENTORING. I created The Bryan Scholar Virtual Mentorship Program to facilitate the professional and personal growth of these students as they accomplish their academic and personal goals. By collaborating with the University Of Maryland School Of Nursing, I was given the opportunity to pilot my program. The results were amazing! My mentees achieved their set goals for the semester and felt a sense of empowerment.

By aligning my passion with my purpose, I will continue to create an environment that will encourage student nurses of color towards successful completion of their educational goals. My goal is to continue empowering the next generation of nurses to become successful professionals and leaders in the healthcare industry.

Experience

Novant Health
Registered Nurse
August 2018 - Present (1 year 11 months)
Charlotte, North Carolina

Working in the PACU, ACU, and ENDO dept

Fusion Medical Staffing
Registered Nurse
June 2016 - July 2018 (2 years 2 months)
Travel Nurse. Worked in the PACU at the following Hospitals:
St. Raphael Hospital, New Haven CT

Beverly Hospital, Beverly MA Intermountain Healthcare, St. George UT

Tufts Medical Center, Boston MA

Cleveland Clinic Registered Nurse February 2015 - April 2016 (1 year 3 months) Abu Dhabi, Abu Dhabi, United Arab Emirates

Functioned in the role of Charge Nurse in the Pre-op and Phase 2 Department.

Also worked in the PACU department.

Assisted with scheduling.

Assisted with orienting new nurses to the department.

Worked with Leadership with recruitment.

Mercy Medical Center, Baltimore, MD Registered Nurse April 2013 - December 2014 (1 year 9 months) Baltimore, Maryland Area

University of Maryland Medical Center Registered Nurse July 2012 - April 2013 (10 months) Baltimore, Maryland Area

Worked in the PACU Department

The Hospital of Central Connecticut Registered Nurse

January 2011 - May 2012 (1 year 5 months)

New Britain, Connecticut

Worked in the ICU Department then transitioned to the PACU Department

Banner Health Registered Nurse April 2006 - December 2010 (4 years 9 months) Phoenix, Arizona

Worked in the MICU Department

Education

University of Connecticut bachelor of nursing, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1995 - 2001)

University of Maryland Baltimore

Master's degree, Nursing Leadership and Management